Another type of wireless network is a cellular
network, which most mobile devices run on.
The highest speed cellular network is 5G though
that network is not available in every area
nor on every mobile device at this time.
Most mobile devices have access to 4G or 4G
LTE, Long-Term Evolution networks, a faster
version of 4G networks.
Some mobile devices only have access to 3G
or 2G networks.
One item to note on mobile device networks
is that speeds vary greatly based on the proximity
of a mobile device to a tower.
Depending upon one's cellular service plan,
one's speeds could be throttled during peak
hours or if a cellular customer exceeds a
certain amount of used bandwidth per billing
period.
Satellite is another type of internet connection
that is prominent in areas to where is no
cable or DSL internet availability and cell
service is not consistent.
Satellite internet is generally faster than
dial-up but the biggest issue with satellites
is latency, the delay from a source to a destination,
as a signal needs to travel up to 20,000 miles
above the Earth and then back down to a destination.
For that reason, satellite internet is not
the best for real-time activities such as
video conferencing and gaming.